<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bruce Changlong Xu on Bruce C. Xu</title><link>https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Bruce Changlong Xu on Bruce C. Xu</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>you@example.com (Bruce Changlong Xu)</managingEditor><webMaster>you@example.com (Bruce Changlong Xu)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Croucher Foundation Cardiovascular Invited Lecture</title><link>https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/posts/crouchercardiovascular/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>you@example.com (Bruce Changlong Xu)</author><guid>https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/posts/crouchercardiovascular/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This summer I had the opportunity to present at the Croucher Foundation Summer Course in Cardiovascular Science, where I shared work developed with my mentors at the Stanford Cardiovascular Institute on immune checkpoint inhibitor–associated myocarditis. This is a rare but highly fatal complication of PD-1 and CTLA-4 blockade, with incidence as low as 0.04–1.4% but mortality approaching 40%. Using single-cell RNA-seq, TCR-seq, and CITE-seq, our group identified a clear axis of disease biology: CXCR3^hi CD8+ T cells clonally expand in the myocardium with upregulated perforin and granzyme programs, while simultaneously a novel macrophage population expressing CXCL9 and CXCL10 emerges. These interferon-inducible chemokines create steep local gradients that recruit and retain the cytotoxic T cells, producing chemokine “niches” in the heart that amplify injury rather than resolving it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Investing in Synchron: Building Cognitive General Intelligence</title><link>https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/posts/synchron/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>you@example.com (Bruce Changlong Xu)</author><guid>https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/posts/synchron/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I first encountered Synchron’s work in endovascular brain–computer interfaces, I saw more than a medical device. I saw a chance to ground the next generation of AI in something that has been missing from our models: human intent. That conviction led me not only to participate in Synchron’s Series D, but to actively advise on how to scale the AI infrastructure behind their system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My contribution has been to help shape a thesis: that the path toward Cognitive General Intelligence (CGI) will not come only from scaling transformers, but from integrating the brain’s own signals of volition into our architectures. At Synchron, that means designing pipelines where neural activity recorded through minimally invasive stentrodes is not treated as noisy data to be decoded, but as a rich supervisory signal that can inform how models learn to represent goals, predict actions, and evaluate outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reflections on Building MC3-Labs with Mayo Clinic</title><link>https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/posts/mc3-labs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>you@example.com (Bruce Changlong Xu)</author><guid>https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/posts/mc3-labs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, I’ve had the privilege of working with colleagues at Mayo Clinic to help establish MC3-Labs (Mayo Clinic Computational &amp;amp; Clinical Collaboration Labs) — a new initiative designed to bridge computational platforms and clinical practice. The mission is simple but ambitious: to weave data, models, and clinical expertise into systems that can truly translate from platform to bedside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In shaping MC3-Labs, I’ve been fortunate to work across several projects that illustrate this vision:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reflections on Organising a Global AI Governance Summit</title><link>https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/posts/hkgagc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>you@example.com (Bruce Changlong Xu)</author><guid>https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/posts/hkgagc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence is advancing faster than the frameworks that might guide its use. Conversations about risk and opportunity are dominated by Washington, Brussels, and Beijing. But if AI is to truly benefit humanity, the conversation cannot remain fragmented — it must be global, inclusive, and grounded in trust. This year, I began organizing the inaugural Hong Kong Global AI Governance Summit alongside one of my closest friends and colleagues. The vision is simple but ambitious: to bring together researchers, policymakers, clinicians, entrepreneurs, and civic leaders from across the U.S., China, and beyond to discuss how we can shape frontier AI toward human flourishing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Towards Oncological Superintelligence</title><link>https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/posts/towards-oncological-superintelligence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>you@example.com (Bruce Changlong Xu)</author><guid>https://brucechanglongxu.github.io/posts/towards-oncological-superintelligence/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cancer has always been a disease of time. Time until the BCR-ABL translocation is recognized in a patient’s marrow; time until sequencing reveals a KRAS mutation in a pancreatic biopsy; time until MYC amplification is confirmed in a lymphoma panel. Time until a therapy is chosen, and then time bought by treatments that stretch survival by months when decades are needed. For patients and families, each interval is both hope and dread. For clinicians, it is the weight of complexity and uncertainty pressed into every decision.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>